[Waco] Evangelia Settlement records, Inclusive: 1912-1975, undated, Bulk: 1936-1970
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
[Waco] Evangelia Settlement records
Inclusive: 1912-1975, undated, Bulk: 1936-1970
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2690
Evangelia Settlement
11 document boxes and 1 oversized box.
The [Waco] Evangelia Settlement records consist of correspondence, legal, financial, literary manuscripts generated by the settlement or written about the settlement along with scrapbooks that contain newspaper clippings and photographs.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Average.
Biography/Profile
Evangelia Settlement was founded in Waco, Texas in 1907 by Ethel Dickson and Nell Symes. It was first located at the intersection of 13th Street and Webster Street. Evangelia Settlement was chartered by the state of Texas on 1912 June 1 in McLennan County, Texas. It was formed for the purpose of "support of benevolent, charitable, educational and missionary undertakings being purely public in its nature." Evangelia Settlement became the first day care program for underprivileged children in Waco.
Evangelia Settlement was one of eighteen known settlement houses in urban areas of Texas in the early 1900s. Settlement houses were established from the 1890s through the early part of the 1900s primarily by white, young, middle-class men and women who were interested in religous and social concerns. These men and women moved into urban areas of cities and established homes where they lived and worked to improve conditions for residents through financial, material, social, and educational venues. Evangelia Settlement served as a daycare facility and over the years transformed into a neighborhood center. The Settlement served as a venue for community activities such as hosting the first Campfire Girls troop in Waco in 1916 and the first Vacation Bible School in Waco in 1918.
In the late 1960s, through private donations and grants from foundations such as the Cooper Foundation and United Way, Evangelia established the Emergency Baby Cottage to provide long-term care to infants and young children. By the 1970s Evangelia was licensed by the state to care for 147 children up to age twelve and had a lengthy waiting list, according to director Rosemary Painter.
Evangelia Settlement continued to make contributions to the greater Waco community by providing childcare to underprivledged children until 2007, when the organization lost legal standing with the state and closed its doors.
Scope and Content
The [Waco] Evangelia Settlement records begin in 1912 and ends in 1975. Legal Documents and Financial Documents are the largest series in the collection. The Legal Documents series contains the incorporation documents for the settlement as well as the Board of Trustees minutes. This series also houses case studies done by Evangelia social workers. The Financial Documents series includes institutional budgets as well as monthly reports on the settlement's income and expenses. The Literary Production Series has newspaper clippings related to Evangelia as well as a contact book. The Scrapbooks series contains two scrapbooks, each primarily composed of clippings.
Arrangement
The [Waco] Evangelia Settlement records were organized prior to this finding aid and folders had titles that matched what was inside. Prior to this finding aid a preliminary listing had been completed.
Currently, the [Waco] Evangelia Settlement records are arranged into six series: I. Correspondence, II. Legal Documents, III. Financial Documents, IV. Literary Productions, V. Photographic Material, and VI. Scrapbooks.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2690. Acquired 1985-04-00
Related Resources
Related collection materials
[Waco] Evangelia Settlement Records: Tejas Council of Camp Fire Collection contains the records of the group that held their first meeting in Waco at Evangelia Settlement.
Related references
Acosta, Teresa Palomo, María-Cristina García, and Cynthia E. Orozco. “Settlement Houses.” Handbook of Texas Online. 2020 Accessed April 28.
Pacey, Lorene M., ed. Readings in the Development of Settlement Work. Freeport, NY: Books for Libraries Press, 1971.
Painter, Rosemary. "Oral memoirs of Rosemary Painter." 1977 March 25. Oral History Institute, Baylor University.
Ryan, Terri Jo. "A child's refuge: Evangelia Settlement provided care for children of working poor." Waco Tribune-Herald (Waco, TX), 2008 October 11.
Trolander, Judith Ann. Settlement Houses and the Great Depression. Detroit: Wayne State University Press, 1975.
Index Terms
Subjects
Benevolence -- Social aspects -- United States.; Day care centers -- Texas.; Nonprofit organizations.; Social settlements -- United States -- History -- 20th century.
Genres
Budgets.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Minutes (Records); Photographs.; Reports.
- Correspondence, 1919-1974, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence associated with Evangelia Settlement. This series includes materials to and from the Cooper Foundation about various grant projects, documentation about the planning of the Emergency Baby Cottage, and information about the estate of Charles and Maud E. Hamilton and the bequest they left to Evangelia Settlement.
  - General, 1919 January-1958 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General, 1966-1974, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cooper Foundation, 1958 January-April (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cooper Foundation, 1958 May-August (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Emergency Baby Cottage, 1966 December-1967 July (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Emergency Baby Cottage, 1967 July-October (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Emergency Baby Cottage, 1967 October-1968 February (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Hamilton Estate, 1939-1957 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Legal Documents, 1912-1971, undated; 2
  General condition: Average.
  This series contains articles of incorporation and bylaws for Evangelia Settlement, as well as multiple versions of the Evangelia Settlement Constitution. Also included are the minutes from board of directors' meetings and legal reports about children served by Evangelia Settlement.
  - Constitution and By-Laws, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1914 December-1916 December (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1917 January-1923 December (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1925 January-1927 September (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1928 February-1929 September (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1929 October-1930 May (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1930 July-November (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1930 December-1934 January (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1934 January-1935 December (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1935 January-December (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1936 February-December (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1937 January-1938 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Legal: Minutes: Board of Directors, 1938 November-1940 January (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1940 February-1941 September (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1941 October-1944 January (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1944 February-1945 September (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1945 October-1946 October (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1946 November-1948 February (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1948 March-November (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1948 December-1949 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1949 July-1950 July (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1950 September-1951 December (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1952 January-1953 March (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1953 April-1954 April (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1954 May-1955 April (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1955 May-1956 July (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1956 September-1957 August (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1957 September-1958 October (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1958 November-1959 December (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1960 January-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1961 January-1962 February (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1962 March-1963 May (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1963 June-1964 September (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1964 October-1965 May (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1965 June-1966 January (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1966 February-April (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1966 May-July (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1966 July-October (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1966 October-December (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 January-February (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 March-April (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 May-June (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 July (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 August-October (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1967 November-December (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 January (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 January-February (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 March-April (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 June-September (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 October-November (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1968 December-1969 January (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1969 February-April (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1969 May-June (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1969 July-September (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, 1969 October-December (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Minutes: Board of Directors, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Reports: Children, 1926-1930 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Reports: Children, 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Children, 1930-1933 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Financial Documents, 1922-1969, undated; 3
  The Financial Document series contains monthly financial reports from Evangelia Settlement that detail monthly expenses and income and provide insight into the activities of the organization during that time. Also included are passbooks, ledgers, audit paperwork and invoices.
  - Financial: Audits, 1933-1944 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Financial: Audits, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Financial: Audits, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Financial: Audits, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Financial: Audits, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Financial: Audits, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Financial: Audits, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Financial: Audits, 1962-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Financial: Audits, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Financial: Audits, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Financial: Audits, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Financial: Bank Pass Books, 1922-1932 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Financial: Budgets, 1933-1939 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 2), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 2), 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 3), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 3), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Financial: Budgets: (3 of 3), 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 4), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 4), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Financial: Budgets: (3 of 4), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Financial: Budgets: (4 of 4), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 4), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 4), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Financial: Budgets: (3 of 4), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Financial: Budgets: (4 of 4), 1967 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 4), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 4), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Financial: Budgets: (3 of 4), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Financial: Budgets: (4 of 4), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Financial: Budgets: (1 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Financial: Budgets: (2 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Financial: Budgets: (3 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Financial: Budgets: (4 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Financial: Budgets: (5 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Financial: Budgets: (6 of 6), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Financial: Invoices: (1 of 3), 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Financial: Invoices: (2 of 3), 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Financial: Invoices: (3 of 3), 1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Financial: Invoices, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Financial: Invoices, 1958-1968 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Financial: Invoices: (1 of 3), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Financial: Invoices: (2 of 3), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Financial: Invoices: (3 of 3), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Financial: Invoices, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Financial: Invoices, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Financial: Ledger: Evangelia Settlement Treasurer, 1932-1943 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Financial: Ledger: Evangelia Settlement Treasurer, 1943-1952 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Financial: Ledger: Evangelia Settlement Treasurer: Loose Materials, 1952-1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Financial: Reports, 1923-1926 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial: Reports, 1927 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Financial: Reports, 1928 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 4), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 4), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 4), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 4), 1929 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Financial: Reports, 1930 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 3), 1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 3), 1931 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 3), 1931 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 4), 1932 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 4), 1932 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 4), 1932 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 4), 1932 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 5), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 5), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 5), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 5), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Financial: Reports: (5 of 5), 1933 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 5), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 5), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 5), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 5), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Financial: Reports: (5 of 5), 1934 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Financial: Reports: (5 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Financial: Reports: (6 of 6), 1935 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 5), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 5), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 5), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 5), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Financial: Reports: (5 of 5), 1936 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Financial: Reports: (5 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Financial: Reports: (6 of 6), 1937 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 3), 1938 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 3), 1938 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 3), 1938 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 3), 1939 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Financial: Reports, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Financial: Reports: (1 of 4), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Financial: Reports: (2 of 4), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Financial: Reports: (3 of 4), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Financial: Reports: (4 of 4), 1957 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Financial: Reports, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Financial: Reports, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Financial: Reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Literary Productions, 1920-1971, undated; 4
  The Literary Production series contains literary reports, printed material, clippings, and three books related to Evangelia Settlement. Reports in this series are primarily related to the board, various fundraisers, the Cooper Foundation and former director Anne Garrett. The book subseries includes a yearbook produced by the Board of Directors, a guestbook signed by visitors to Evangelia Settlement, and a contact book compiled by social workers.
  - General, 1959-1967, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Reports: Cooper Foundation, 1957-1959 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Reports: Cooper Foundation, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Reports: Cooper Foundation, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Reports: Cooper Foundation, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Reports: Cooper Foundation, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Reports: Board Members, 1926-1966 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Reports: Board Members, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Reports: Anne Garrett, 1960-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Reports: Title IV-A Funds (1 of 2), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Reports: Title IV-A Funds (2 of 2), 1972 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council (1 of 4), 1962 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council (2 of 4), 1962 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council (3 of 4), 1962 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council (4 of 4), 1962 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Reports: Action Planning Council, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Books: Contact Book, 1960-1962 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Books: Guest Book, 1959-1971, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Books: Yearbook: Board of Directors, 1948-1956 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Books: Yearbook: Board of Directors, 1956-1959 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Books: Yearbook: Board of Directors, 1960-1964 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Printed Materials: History, 1920, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Printed Materials: History, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Printed Materials: Budget Manual, 1955-1956 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Printed Materials: YES for Youth Building Fund, 1956-1974 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Printed Materials: Buildings, 1953-1966 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Printed Materials: Real Estate, 1954-1967 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, 1960-1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Clippings, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Clippings (1 of 3), undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Clippings (2 of 3), undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Clippings (3 of 3), undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Photographic Materials, 1975, undated; 5
  The Photographic Material series contains photographs related to Evangelia Settlement. The majority of the pictures are of the children who went to Evangelia Settlement. The photographs are grouped by type and include depictions of children at the playground, indoors, and during meal times. There are also photographs from Christmas and other special events.
  - Children at Playground, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Individual Children, 1975, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 2)
  - Children and Indoor Activities, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Children at Meal, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Children with Guests at Meal, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Christmas and Special Events, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - General, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 7)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1920-1942, undated; 6
  The Scrapbooks series contains four scrapbooks. Two scrapbooks consist primarily of newspaper clippings. One of these scrapbooks has a drawing of the floor plan for the Emergency Baby Cottage. The other scrapbook primarily consisting of newspaper clippings has a page with three photographs of children at a Christmas event. The other two scrapbooks consist primarily of photographs and literary productions, such as programs and other printed materials. The series is in fair to good condition.
  - Scrapbooks: (1 of 3), 1936-1942, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks: (2 of 3), 1936-1942, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbooks: (3 of 3), 1936-1942, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbooks: (1 of 2), undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbooks: (2 of 2), undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbooks: (1 of 3), circa 1920 (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbooks: (2 of 3), circa 1920 (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbooks: (3 of 3), circa 1920 (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 15)
  - Photograph information sheets for 1920s scrapbooks, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook, circa 1930 (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 17)
  - Photograph information sheets for 1930s scrapbook, undated (Box 12 OVZ, Folder 18)